(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-01T23:12:00.565258",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あたしタランちゃま！ クモ人間なの！
I'm Taran-chama! I'm a spider-person!
お前を食べちゃうぞ〜〜〜！
I'm gonna eat you up~!
うふふ！ だめだよ〜〜！
Ehehe! No way~!
ずっとみんな、なかよし！
We'll all be best friends forever!
うふふ やくそくだよ？
Ehehe, that's a promise, okay?
あなたは今 どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you right now, and what are you doing?
この空の 続く場所に いますか？
Are you somewhere beneath this continuous sky?
今までの私の心を 埋めていたもの
The things that had filled my heart until now...
失って 初めて気づいた
...I only realized after I lost them.
こんなにも私を 支えてくれていたこと
How much you supported me...
こんなにも笑顔を くれたこと
...and gave me so many smiles.
失ってしまった代償は
The cost of losing it all...
とてつもなく大きすぎて
...was far too immense to bear.
取り戻そうと必死に
Desperately trying to regain it...
手を伸ばしてもがくけれど
...I reach out my hands and struggle, but...
まるで風のようにすり抜けて
...like the wind, it slips right through.
届きそうで届かない
It feels so close, yet remains out of reach.
孤独と絶望に胸を締め付けられ
Strangled by loneliness and despair...
心が壊れそうになるけれど
...my heart feels on the verge of breaking, but...
思い出に残るあなたの笑顔が
...your smile lingering in my memories...
私をいつも励ましてくれる
...always gives me courage.
もう一度あの頃に戻ろう
Let us return to those days once again.
今度はきっと大丈夫
This time, I know everything will be alright.
いつもそばで笑っていよう
Let's always be smiling by each other's side.
あなたのすぐ傍で
Right by your side.
あなたは今 どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you right now, and what are you doing?
何の続く場所にいますか
Are you in a place where something continues?
いつものように笑顔でいてくれますか
Will you keep smiling as you always do?
今はただそれを願い続ける
Now, I just keep wishing for that.
生誕ライブ限定！グッズ販売のお知らせ！！
Birthday Live Exclusive! Merchandise Sales Announcement!!
家族写真B2タペストリー！ゴージャスな額縁風デザインと肖像画のような二人がとってもキュート！お部屋の壁に今日の思い出を飾って、彩り豊かな推し活ができちゃいます！
Family Photo B2 Tapestry! The gorgeous frame-like design and portrait-like duo are so cute! Decorate your wall with memories to brighten up your fan life!
おでかけちゃまぬいぐるみ タランちゃまドレス衣装ver.！ボタン風の目がとっても可愛い！丁寧に再現されたドレス衣装のちゃまと一緒におでかけして旅に出れちゃいます！
Outing-Chama Plushie (Taran-Chama Dress Outfit ver.)! The button-like eyes are super cute! Go out on trips with Chama in her meticulously recreated dress outfit!
タランちゃまぬいぐるみポーチ！背中のファスナーが開いて収納できる便利アイテム。ゴスロリ衣装のタランちゃまが可愛すぎる！チェーンが付いてるから、安心してお散歩させられるよ！
Taran-Chama Plushie Pouch! A handy item with a back zipper for storage. Gothic Lolita Taran-Chama is way too cute! Comes with a chain so you can take her on walks safely!
タランちゃまスマホリング！スマホの落下はタランちゃまにお任せ！しっかり張り付いて守ってくれます！愛くるしいお目目と、つい目が合っちゃう瞬間も…癒されてたまりません！
Taran-Chama Smartphone Ring! Leave preventing phone drops to Taran-Chama! She sticks firmly to protect your phone! Those adorable eyes that lock with yours are so comforting!
フルセット購入特典の数量限定バージョンは、箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと、赤井はあと直筆サイン！特典ボイス「ひみつのはなし」もあるよ！
The limited quantity full set bonus includes a postcard with a foil-stamped message and Akai Haato's handwritten signature! Includes bonus voice "Secret Talk"!
ホロライブ公式ECサイトで販売中！
Now available on the Hololive Official EC Site!
ひとつだけ、ただひとつだけ見つけたものは
The only thing, the one single thing I found
誠実で不器用な、それでも柔らかかな声
Was an honest, clumsy, yet soft voice.
朽ちてゆき、ただ崩れゆく、世界を照らす
Illuminating a world decaying, simply crumbling away,
暖かで、でも残酷な、去り際の笑顔
A warm, yet cruel smile as you departed.
ひび割れてく翡翠の水槽を満たすもの
What fills this cracking jade aquarium...
「永遠ではない」なんて、初めから解ってたのに…
Even though I knew from the start, "Nothing lasts forever"...
壊れても、なお美しく、胸を刻むのは
What leaves an imprint on my heart, still beautiful even if broken,
砕けても、なお美しい、ひとひらの記憶
Is a single petal of memory, still beautiful even when shattered.
忘れたいのに、なお狂おしく、胸に残るのは
Though I want to forget, what maddeningly lingers in my chest
痛みさえ忘れさせた、微かな感触
Is a faint touch that made me forget even the pain.
ひとつだけ、ただひとつだけ伝えたのは
The only thing, the one single thing I conveyed
冷たさで誤魔化した、苦し紛れの嘘
Was a desperate lie disguised with coldness.
愛しくて、ただ愛しくて、選んだ言葉は
So dear, so beloved, the words I chose
すべて終わらせる偽りのセリフ
Were fake words to bring an end to everything.
風が吹けば飛ぶような砂に残した手紙
A letter left in the sand, so fragile a breeze could blow it away...
「永遠ではない」ということさえ忘れられたのに…
Even though I was able to forget that "nothing lasts forever"...
Even the fact that "it is not eternal" was forgotten...
もう一度、もう一度と、もう何度思ったでしょう
How many times must I have thought, "Just once more, just once more"?
枯れた花束、捨てられもせず
Unable to even throw away the withered bouquet...
降り止まぬ雨は、まるで万雷の拍手喝采
The relentless rain is like a thunderous ovation,
愚かな後悔を 嗤う怒涛のよう
like a surging wave mocking my foolish regret.
壊れても、なお美しく、胸を刻むのは
What carves into my chest, still beautiful even if broken,
砕けても、なお美しい、ひとひらの記憶
is a single petal of memory, still beautiful even if shattered.
忘れたいのに、なお狂おしく、胸に残るのは
Though I want to forget, what maddeningly remains in my heart...
痛みさえ忘れさせた、微かな感触
...is a faint sensation that made me even forget the pain.
微かな感触
A faint sensation.
「なんで」
Why?
「いなくなっちゃったの…」
Why did you disappear...?
「こんなの苦しいよ…」
This hurts so much...
「そばにいて…」
Stay by my side...
「いつも、そばにいるよ。」
"I'll always be by your side."
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you already forgotten?
夏の木陰に座ったまま
Sitting in the summer shade,
アイスを口に放り込んで風を待っていた
popping ice cream into our mouths, waiting for the breeze.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you already forgotten?
世の中の全部嘘だらけ
How everything in this world is full of lies,
本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと笑ったこと
and how we laughed, saying we'd go search for true value together?
忘れないように
So that I won't forget,
色褪せないように
so that it won't fade,
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
so that physical things aren't everything...
言葉をもっと教えて
Teach me more words,
夏が来るって教えて
tell me that summer is coming.
僕は描いてる
I'm picturing it;
眼に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
reflected in my eyes is the ghost of summer.
風にスカートが揺れて
My skirt sways in the wind,
思い出なんて忘れて
forgetting all about memories.
浅い呼吸をする
Breathing shallow breaths,
汗を拭って夏めく
wiping away sweat as summer approaches.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you already forgotten?
夏の木陰に座った頃
Back when we sat in the summer shade,
遠くの丘から顔出した雲があったじゃないか
remember the clouds peeking over the distant hill?
君はそれを掴もうとして
You tried to reach out and catch them,
馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
with hands grasping foolishly at the air.
僕は紙に雲一つを書いて
I drew a cloud on a piece of paper,
笑って握って見せて
and showed it to you with a smile.
忘れないように
So that I won't forget,
色褪せないように
so that it won't fade,
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
because things left in history aren't everything.
今だけ顔も失くして
For now, let's lose our faces,
言葉も全部忘れて
and forget all our words.
君は笑ってる
You are smiling,
夏を待ってる
waiting for summer.
僕ら亡霊だ
We are ghosts
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart
夏の匂いを教えて
Tell me the smell of summer
浅い呼吸をする
Breathe shallowly
忘れないように
So I will not forget
色褪せないように
So it does not fade
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
Because what touches your heart isn't everything
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words
さよならだって教えて
Tell me how to say goodbye
今も見るんだよ 夏に咲いてる花に亡霊を
I still see them: ghosts in the flowers blooming in summer
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Not words, but time
時間じゃなくて心を
Not time, but heart
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away sweat, taking on the feel of summer
夏の匂いがする
It smells of summer
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you already forgotten?
夏の木陰に座ったまま
Sitting in the shade of summer
アイスを口に放り込んで
Stuffing ice cream into our mouths
風を待っていた
Waiting for the breeze
ということで、赤井はあと爆誕生祭2025！
And with that, Akai Haato Super Birthday Fest 2025!
始まっちゃまー！
Is starting-chama!
おー、事故事故事故！あぶないあぶない！
Whoa, collision, collision! Dangerous!
1曲目！1曲目まだ！体調考慮しないと！
First song! Still on the first song! We need to pace ourselves!
ゲストに来てくれたのは...らでんちゃん！
The guest who joined us today is... Raden-chan!
こんばんは！ホロライブDEV_IS ReGLOSSの儒烏風亭らでんでございます！
Good evening! I am Juufuutei Raden from Hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS!
ありがとうー！来てくれてー！ / 先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Thank you for coming! / Senpai, happy birthday!
そして、新衣装じゃないですかー！
And look, aren't these new outfits?!
そうなのー！きれい！かわいい！イエーイ！
That's right! Pretty! Cute! Yay!
いや、この衣装めっちゃシナジーある！ / ある！
Seriously, these outfits have such great synergy! / They do!
なんからでんちゃん言ってたけど、これクリスマスカラーだね、この2人！
Like Raden-chan was saying earlier, we're in Christmas colors, the two of us!
ね！イエーイ！らでんはクリスマスツリー！
Right! Yay! Raden is the Christmas tree!
そう！はあちゃまは...サンタ！
Yes! Haachama is... Santa!
サンタです！ / サンタ！
It's Santa! / Santa!
で、この季節にぴったり...
And so perfect for this season...
ぴったり...夏...夏の匂いがしますか？
Perfect for... summer... does it smell like summer?
クリスマスなんてあると思ってねえよ！
Who ever thought of Christmas being now?!
ハッシュタグもね、#赤井はあと爆誕生祭2025 でね...
And the hashtag is #AkaiHaatoSuperBirthdayFest2025...
ぜひともSNSでスクショとかツイートしてください！
Please post screenshots and tweets on social media!
じゃあ、なんか写真撮ろっか！ / 写真撮りましょう！おしとやかなポーズいきますか？
Then, shall we take a picture? / Let's take photos! Should we go with an elegant pose?
じゃあ...ジャーン！おしとやか...？
Then... Tada! Is this elegant...?
ガッツリね！ / ガッツリ！
Going all out! / All out!
キメポーズ！おしとやかなポーズ！
Strike a pose! An elegant pose!
これ、いいんじゃない？ / ホロライブ...
Isn't this good? / Hololive...
強さ！強そう！ / 強そう！先輩！
Strength! Looks strong! / Looks strong, Senpai!
えー、じゃあ...どうしようかな...
Um, well then... what should we do...
あ、ちょっとハート目で... / 今どきのハートで！いいんじゃないスか？
Ah, let's do heart-eyes... / A modern heart pose! Isn't this great?
そして、そして、そして...
And then, and then, and then...
ハート！ / ハート！
Heart! / Heart!
あー！いいやん！ / らでんちゃん、いいんじゃない？
Ah! That's good! / Raden-chan, isn't that nice?
戻ってきて！戻ってきて！ / うちらの中じゃないスか！
Come back! Come back! / Isn't that between us?!
あははは！危ない危ない！
Ahahaha! Dangerous, dangerous!
やばいやばい！ / 今のね、今の喝を入れただけだから！
Oh no, oh no! / That was... I was just giving a pep talk!
喝を入れさせていただきました！ / 揉めたりとかしないからね、別に！
I just gave us a little pep talk! / It's not like we're fighting or anything!
ほら！しっとりした曲歌った後ですから！
Look! We just sang a solemn song after all!
しゃなりと...しゃなりとね！
Elegantly... elegantly, right!
みんなスクショ撮ってくれてるかな？ / ツイートしてね！
I wonder if everyone is taking screenshots? / Tweet them okay!
そんなわけで...
Anyway...
今回ですね、我々は... / なんかホロライブ...
This time, we are... / Like, Hololive...
そうですよ！我々ユニット名『ホロライブ』ですから！
That's right! Our unit name is 'Hololive'!
というわけでね、らでんちゃんに来てもらいました！
And so, we had Raden-chan join us!
ありがとうございますね
Thank you so much.
あの 衣装もシナジーがあるということで
Also, our outfits have great synergy,
「花に亡霊」をね 歌ったんですけど どうでした？
we sang "Ghost in a Flower", so how was it?
え もう...
Um, well...
いや え もう このステージ すっごく合ってたし
No, like, really... it fit this stage so well!
いや やっぱりね ラレーンちゃんに歌ってほしいパートがあったんですよ
And I really had parts I wanted Raren-chan to sing!
どこどこどこ？
Where, where, where?
「歴史に残るものだけがすべてじゃない」っていうところでね
Like the line "What remains in history isn't everything".
これちょっとラレーンちゃんに歌ってほしいなと思って
I thought, "I really want Raren-chan to sing this part."
パート割を分けさせてもらいました
So I assigned the parts like that!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
私もしで歌いたいなと思ってた曲だったから
Because it was a song I wanted to cover somewhere too!
あ そうなんだ！よかった！
Oh, really? I'm so glad!
そう 「この曲一緒に歌いたいんだ」って言ってくれただけで
Yeah, just hearing you say "I want to sing this song together"...
超嬉しい！と思って！
...made me super happy!
よかった！嬉しい！
I'm so glad! I'm happy too!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
じゃあ... じゃあ気をつけて帰ってね
Well then... make sure to get home safely!
ここから？！ここから？！えっ？！
From here?! From right here?! Huh?!
じゃ... じゃあほな！ほな！
Well... see ya then! Bye-bye!
これから頑張ってください！
Good luck with the rest!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
これどうやって帰るの？これどうやって帰るの？
How do I get back from here? How do I get back?
あっちあっち！あ こっち！あっち！
Over there! Ah, this way! Over there!
あ あっちとかこっちとかあるんだこういうのって
Ah, so there is an "over there" and "this way" for things like this!
あ 木が！危ない！
Ah, a tree! Watch out!
ありがとー！頑張ってくださーい！バイバーイ！
Thank you~! Good luck~! Bye-bye~!
はるか遠い遠い昔 巻かれた首輪は
A long, long time ago, a collar was placed on me.
人が欲しい人が欲しいと叫ぶ呪いの首輪は
"I want someone, I want someone," screams the cursed collar.
怒らないで見捨てないでどこもいかないで
Don't get angry, don't abandon me, don't go anywhere...
強く締める吐くまで締める人がいないいないと
Tighten it hard, choke until I vomit, saying there's no one, no one...
いい成績でしょう
Good grades, right?
ねえねえ いい子でしょう
Hey, hey, I'm a good child, right?
かわいい子でしょう
A cute child, right?
ねえねえ 良い子でしょう
Hey, hey, I'm a good child, right?
苦しいねえ
It hurts, you know?
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more,
愛して 愛して 狂おしいほどに
love me, love me, to the point of madness.
苦しい 苦しい 呪縛を解いて 解いてねえ
It hurts, it hurts, break this curse, break it, please...
止められない
It can't be stopped.
身体 身体 大きくなっても小さい首輪
Even as my body grows bigger, the collar stays small.
苦しくなる足りなくなる人が人が足りない
It hurts, it's not enough, people, people aren't enough.
クラスの誰にも負けないキレイないい子でしょう
I'm a pretty, good child, second to no one in class, right?
ねえ あの子よりもどの子よりも誰も彼も私を見てよ
Hey, more than that child, more than any child, everyone, look at me!
体育館裏 あなたに告白を
Behind the gymnasium, I confess my love to you.
嘘みたいでしょう
It seems like a lie, right?
あなたが好きの 汚いあなたが
I love you—the dirty you.
愛して 愛して 愛して 全部あげる
Love me, love me, love me, I'll give you everything,
あなたに あなたに 全部背負ってもらうよ
I'll make you bear everything for me.
足りない あなたが足りない 離さないよ
Not enough, you're not enough, I won't let go...
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more,
愛して 愛して 狂おしいほどに
love me, love me, to the point of madness.
苦しいほどに
So much that it hurts,
苦しい
it hurts,
狂おしいほどに
to the point of madness,
もっともっとねえ
more and more, hey...
幸せなの
I'm happy...
しあわせなの...
Am I happy...?
Nerissa, Ina, thank you for coming!
Wait, wait, chainsaw! Wait, wait, wait!
This is unfair! We need weapons too! I need one too!
I have a chainsaw too! Oh wow, that's heavy!
Okay, it's a little heavy. Let me try! Let's go!
Yeah!
I feel so 努力 未来 A BEAUTIFUL STAR!
I feel so... effort, future, a beautiful star!
Ina-sen, I wanna... chainsaw! 努力 未来 A BEAUTIFUL STAR!
Ina-sen, I wanna... chainsaw! Effort, future, star!
愛して 愛して 愛して お願い
Love me, love me, love me, please...
Yeah, I'm so happy to sing together! Happy Birthday!
Happy to sing together! Happy Birthday, Haachama!
Happy Birthday! Yay!
It's a really nice birthday today!
Thank you for letting us celebrate it with you!
That was so fun! Yeah!
It's the first time we... the EN group!
Ina, Nerissa, and Haachama... We are...
HaCHAMARISA! We just remade it!
HACHAMARISA! We just made it up!
We just jumbled our names together! HaCHAMARISA!
Let's take a picture! Okay, okay!
Everyone take a picture!
Nice! That was a good screenshot!
Yeah! That's so cool!
No no no no no! Dangerous, dangerous!
Let's kill... let's kill them! The camera? Camera!
Let's kill... let me kill them! Camera? Camera!
Say goodbye!
ねぇ 私知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know... that you're alone.
知ってるの 知ってるよ ぴくぴく震えてさ 今夜も孤立さ なんだわ
I know, I know. You're trembling tonight too.
正直に言っちゃいよ 呼ばれてるんだし 言っちゃいよ 「消えたいの？」
Just be honest, say it... "Do you want to disappear?"
うつうつ恥ずかしい みんな隠しているだけ
Feeling gloomy is embarrassing, but everyone hides it.
ねぇ 私知ってるよ 君がひとり 涙しているの
Hey, I know... that you're shedding tears alone.
知ってるよ ぐすんぐすんへこんでさ 弱音吐くのっていいんじゃない？
I know. Isn't it okay to show weakness?
朝が来るまで言い尽くそう 持ってないってなんだって 受け止めてあげる
Let's talk until morning. I'll accept all you lack.
もう我慢しないで いっぱい出してね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out.
ほら お願い 君が欲しいの 慰めさせて
Come on, please, I want you. Let me comfort you.
シェイクシェイク 愛の才能で 泣いてくれなきゃ 枯れてしまう くだらない？
Shake shake, with love's talent. Cry for me or I'll wither.
ねぇいいでしょ ナメ取って 呑み干したい たったったっだッ！
Isn't it fine? I want to lick it up and drink it all!
ほら お願い 君が欲しいの 手を散らして シックラブ
Please, I want you. Reaching out with sick love.
なんて最高ね 分けてくれないか？ 君の痛い 試した痛い
Isn't it great? Share your pain that I want to test.
ねぇいいでしょ 吸い取って 救いたい たったったっだッ！
Isn't it fine? I want to absorb it and save you!
見たい見たい見たい見たい... 君の中
I want to see, want to see... inside of you.
見た見た見た見た...
I saw it, saw it, saw it...
ねぇ 私知ってるよ 君がひとり 悔しがってんの
Hey, I know... that you're suffering all alone.
知ってるよ ずくんずくん痛む心 君を汚す言葉許せない
I know. I can't forgive words that hurt you.
ねぇ 私知ってるよ 君の歩く姿
Hey, I know... the way you walk.
知ってるよ 辛い時は 弱いくらいでちょうどいい 私それでも好きだよ
I know. When it's tough, it's fine to be weak.
ほら お願い 君が欲しいの 名前を呼んでよ いつだって
Please, I want you. Call my name anytime.
愛情参上 君はひとりだ だから歌う 独り占め
Love has arrived. I sing to keep you to myself.
ねぇいいでしょ その痛みはお仕舞い たったったっだッ！
Isn't it fine? That pain is over now!
君が病める時も
Even when you're sick...
私 そばにいるわ
I'll be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ
I'm always watching over you.
そう 何も怖くないのよ
Yes, there's nothing to be afraid of.
おねがい 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you.
慰めさせて Shake Shake 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you with the talent of love, shake, shake.
泣いてくれなきゃ 枯れてしまう 濡れていたいの
If you don't cry for me, I'll wither away; I want to be drenched.
なんで言いるの？ 舐めとって 飲み干したい
Why say that? I want to lick it up and drink it dry.
た た た たば
Ta-ta-ta-ta-ba!
おねがい 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you.
手繰り寄せて 散らして シ・ラ・フ なんて最高ね
Pulling you close, scattering... Being sober is the best, isn't it?
化けてくれなきゃ
If you don't transform for me...
君の痛い 感じてたい 慰めてたい
I want to feel your pain, I want to comfort you.
すごい痛って すごい痛い
Saying "it hurts so much", it hurts so much!
た た た たば
Ta-ta-ta-ta-ba!
ねぇ あたし 知ってるよ
Hey, I know...
君のこと ちゃんと知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know all about you, I really know, I know.
グサッと刺さった
Pierced deeply through...
弱い人からいいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to start with the weak ones?
朝が来るまで
Until morning comes,
一緒だから
we're together...
求め合いたくて
Wanting each other...
何度も抱き受け止めてあげる
I'll embrace and accept you again and again.
我慢しないで 出してってば
Don't hold back, just let it out!
諦めの悪い奴から
Starting with the ones who refuse to give up,
音の出口へ
head toward the sound's exit.
飛ぶだの跳ねるだのカーニバル
Jumping and bouncing, it's a carnival.
くわばら くわばら くわばら
Kuwabara, kuwabara, kuwabara.
身の程知らんハイパー
Over-the-top with no sense of limits,
ダンダンダンダン上がるから
rising up step by step.
おひとついかがのまま
"How about one?" as it stays,
戯言になっちゃうなら
if it turns into nonsense,
俺はもう一人のあなた
I'm another version of you.
さあさ今夜は黄泉の国へいざなう
Come, tonight I'll invite you to the underworld.
4時44分 まだら
4:44 AM, spotted...
4時44分44秒 まだら
4:44:44 AM, spotted...
鏡の中 呼び声がしたなら
If a voice calls out from within the mirror,
もう一人 お疲れ様よ
to the other one: good work today.
ハイレタ ハイレタ ハイレタ ハイレタ
I got in, I got in, I got in, I got in.
必死で這い出た先で霧は晴れた
Beyond where I desperately crawled out, the fog cleared.
凸と凹が上手く噛み合ったら
When the convex and concave fit together perfectly,
痛みが重なったら
when the pains overlap...
ココロ カラダ アタマ
Mind, body, head,
みなぎっていく
overflowing.
なんだか背中に今羽が生えたならば
If wings were to sprout on my back right now,
暗闇からおさらば
farewell to the darkness,
飛び立っていく彼方
flying off into the distance.
ココロ カラダ アタマ
Mind, body, head,
懐かしい暖かさ
a nostalgic warmth.
足元に今花が咲いたならば
If flowers were to bloom at my feet right now,
暗闇からおさらば
farewell to the darkness,
飛び立っていく彼方
flying off into the distance.
何度だって生きる お前や君の中
I will live again and again, inside you.
瞳の裏や耳の中
Behind your eyelids, inside your ears,
胸の奥に居着いてる メロディー リズムに
residing deep in your chest, in the melody, in the rhythm.
今日も賽の河原の真ん中
Today as well, in the middle of Sai no Kawara,
積み上げてく Top Top
stacking them up to the top, top.
鬼とチャンバラ
Sword fighting with demons,
The lyrical massacre
ただの大海原
Just a vast ocean,
花を咲かせぃ Sharala
make flowers bloom, sha-ra-la.
祓いたいなら まだまだのさらば
If you want to exorcise it, still a long way from goodbye.
誰が開いたかパンドラ あとは何があっても知らんがな
Who opened Pandora's box? Whatever happens next, I don't care.
数百年跨ぎ久しぶりの喋り場
A chatting spot after centuries of waiting.
楽屋は楽屋でまあるくおさまる話じゃねえよ
This isn't a topic that ends peacefully in the green room.
バカが今確かに目が合ったな
Idiot, our eyes definitely just met.
こういうことかいシャマラー
Is this what it's about?
ハイレタ ハイレタ ハイレタ ハイレタ
I got in, I got in, I got in, I got in.
眠り飽きた先で君が待ってた
Tired of sleeping, you were waiting at the end.
盾と矛が硬く抱き合ったら
When the shield and spear embrace tightly,
怒りが消え去ったら
when the anger vanishes...
ココロ カラダ アタマ
Mind, body, head,
みなぎっていく
overflowing.
なんだか背中に今羽が生えたならば
If wings were to sprout on my back right now,
暗闇からおさらば
farewell to the darkness,
飛び立っていく彼方
flying off into the distance.
ココロ カラダ アタマ
Mind, body, head,
懐かしい暖かさ
a nostalgic warmth.
足元に今花が咲いたならば
If flowers were to bloom at my feet right now,
暗闇からおさらば
farewell to the darkness,
飛び立っていく彼方
flying off into the distance.
何度だって生きる お前や君の中
I will live again and again, inside you.
瞳の裏や耳の中
Behind your eyelids, inside your ears,
胸の奥に居着いてる メロディー リズムに
residing deep in your chest, in the melody, in the rhythm.
ちゃま...
Chama...
たいせつな...
Precious...
かぞく...
family...
爆誕ライブの途中ですが
We're in the middle of the birthday live stream,
ここからはちょっと外にくり出して
but from here, we're going outside a bit
ロケをして行こうと思います
to do an on-location shoot.
ここはですね...
Right here, you see...
私が前から会いたかった方の
The person I've wanted to meet for a while...
ご自宅ということなんですが
This is their home, apparently,
何やら とんでもない雰囲気が漂ってます
and there's an intense atmosphere in the air.
この階段の先に…
At the top of these stairs...
オカルト界隈でも有名な
famous even in occult circles,
呪物コレクターの方があるはずなので
a cursed object collector should be here,
早速 突撃してみたいと思います
so I'm going to barge right in!
行きましょう ドキドキ
Let's go... My heart is pounding!
結構 階段の段差が…
These stairs are pretty steep...
うおぉ めっちゃ暗い
Whoa, it's so dark...
一番奥のお部屋のはずなので
It should be the room at the very end,
先に進んで行きましょう
so let's head further in.
なんかスゴイ… 異質ですね
It's so... strange.
この部屋なんですね
Ah, it's this room.
この一番奥の部屋のはずなので
It should be this room at the very back,
ちょっと… 表札もないですが
and while there's no nameplate,
一応ノックしてみますか？
shall we try knocking anyway?
あれ… ここであってますかね？
Huh... Is this the right place?
もう一度ノックしてみますか
Shall we try knocking once more?
はい
Yes?
声が…
A voice...
あ、どうも
Ah, hello.
あ、どうも 田中さんですか？
Ah, hello. Are you Mr. Tanaka?
はい
Yes.
ホロライブ1期生の赤井はあとと申します
I'm Akai Haato from Hololive Gen 1.
インタビュー撮影に来たんですが
I came to film an interview...
もし良かったら撮影… 大丈夫ですか？
If it's okay, is filming... alright?
大丈夫ですよ
It's fine.
ホントですか？ ありがとうございます
Really? Thank you so much.
約束してましたっけ？
Did we have an appointment?
すいません
I'm sorry.
忘れてました？
Did you forget?
ちょっと忘れてましたね
I kind of forgot, yeah.
すでになんか… 色々見えてますけども
Although I can already see quite a few things...
入ってもいいですか？
May I come in?
はい
Yes.
はい お願いします
Thank you.
お邪魔しまーす 失礼します
Pardon me for intruding.
これ全部 呪物なんですか？
Are all of these cursed objects?
そうなんですよね… 呪物というか まぁ… 呪われた…
That's right... Or rather, cursed...
呪われちゃってるんだ
They're actually cursed...
田中さんは大丈夫なんですか？
Are you okay, Mr. Tanaka?
いやでもずっとしんどいですよ
Well, I've been feeling rough the whole time.
ええ！？
Ehh!?
全部ちゃんと呪われてる…？
Everything is properly cursed...?
中にはまあ… あの…
Among them, well...
良い物もありますけど
there are good ones too.
呪いにも種類があるんですか？
Are there different types of curses?
ありますね
There are.
ちなみに 今配信を見ている人たちのために
By the way, for the viewers watching the stream,
田中さんがどんな方なのか
could you introduce yourself
自己紹介してもらってもよろしいですか？
and tell us what kind of person you are?
呪物コレクター 田中俊行です よろしくお願いします
I'm Toshiyuki Tanaka, a cursed object collector. Nice to meet you.
よろしくお願いします
Nice to meet you!
仕事は怪談師なんですよ
My job is a ghost story teller.
そうなんだ
Oh, I see!
趣味・ライフワークで
And as a hobby and my life's work...
呪われたものを集めてる
I collect cursed items.
今田中さんが立ってる奥の部屋にも
In that back room you're standing near,
呪物があるんですか？
are there cursed objects in there too?
元々こっちだけが呪物部屋だったんですけど
Originally only this room was the cursed room,
量が入り切れなくなって
but I ran out of space for all the items.
奥に入れれたりするんですか？
So you put them in the back room?
奥入れますけど… 奥は比較的
I put them in the back, but the back is relatively
僕が個人的に契約してる呪物が多い
full of cursed objects I personally have contracts with,
入らない方がいい
so it's better not to enter.
あんま多分 呪物嫌がると思います
I think the cursed objects would dislike it.
そんな感じなんだ
Ah, I see.
最初にここ入って 1番気になったのが…
When I first came in here, what caught my eye the most...
赤いお面の横にある 白いお面で
was that white mask next to the red mask.
あれはどういう呪物なんですか？
What kind of cursed object is that?
あれは“呪いの面”って言われてて
That one is called the "Curse Mask",
つけると不幸になると言われている
and it's said that if you put it on, misfortune will fall upon you.
実際に不幸が起こっちゃった人がいる？
Has anyone actually experienced misfortune from it?
います
There are.
京都の蓮久寺っていうお寺
At a temple in Kyoto called Renkyu-ji,
そこに三木大雲さんという和尚がいる
there's a monk named Daiun Miki.
三木大雲さんから預かったもので
I was entrusted with this by Monk Daiun Miki.
たぶんこれ ピー だと思いますけど
I'll probably have to bleep this out, but...
自主規制 と 自主規制 がつけた
some [censored] and [censored] put it on.
つけたの…！？
They put it on...!?
なんでつけちゃったんですか？
Why did they put it on?
そういう番組があった
There was a TV show like that,
試しにつけちゃえみたいな
where they put it on just to try it out.
がっつり呪われちゃいましたね…
And they got completely cursed...
ちゃんと呪われてるぅ…
They really got cursed...
基本 お祓いが済んでない
Basically, items that haven't been exorcised
ものが ここでは普通です
are the norm here.
だから僕も 呪物受け取る時に
So when I receive cursed objects,
人を呪ったものとかありますけど
even ones used to curse people,
「お祓いはやめてくれ」って言います
I tell them, "Please don't exorcise it."
珍しいw
That's unusual!
意味がなくなるので
Because then it loses its purpose.
田中さんおすすめの呪物ありますか？
Do you have any recommended cursed objects, Mr. Tanaka?
あります あります
I do, I do.
じゃあちょっと持ってきますわ
Let me go bring one out.
お願いしま〜す！
Please do!
お人形さんだ！
An old doll!
奥の部屋あれですよね？
The back room is that one, right?
契約の部屋ですけど…
It's the contract room, but...
大丈夫なんですか…？
Is it okay...?
出せっていうから…
Because you told me to bring it out...
あ、でも可愛い…
Ah, but it's cute...
可愛いなんか
It's pretty cute, actually.
ジェラピケ着てるの？
Is it wearing Gelato Pique?
なんでお気に入りなんですか？
Why is this one your favorite?
こう… 呪物を集める…
Well... collecting cursed objects...
呪物を集める
Collecting cursed objects...
集めるきっかけになった人形
The doll that triggered the collection.
どういうきっかけで？
What kind of trigger was it?
元々怪談ライブとかやってたら
Originally, when I was doing ghost story live events,
お客さんが持ってくるんですよね
the audience members would bring them to me.
ええぇ…w
Ehh... (lol)
お祓いとか出来ると思われてて
They thought I could perform exorcisms or something.
ちなみに(お人形の)お名前はなんて？
By the way, what's the doll's name?
チャーミーって
Her name is Charmy.
チャーミーさん
Charmy-san.
関西のある介護施設にいたんですよ
She was at a nursing home in Kansai.
へぇ〜そうなんですね
Huh~ Is that so?
誰が持ってきたかスタッフの人もわからない
No one on staff knew who brought her in.
スタッフの人もわからない
Even the staff didn't know.
特定の利用者の人が可愛がるんですよ 何故か
For some reason, specific residents would adore her.
え、あっ、へぇー
Eh, ah, heeh...
可愛がると三日以内に◯ぬんですよ
When someone adored her, they'd die within three days.
えっ…
What...?
それが5人続いたので
That happened to five people in a row.
5人も続いたんですね…
Five people in a row...
なので一度地下の倉庫に隠した
So they once hid her in the basement storage room.
隠されちゃったんだ
She got hidden away.
次の日には出てきてた
By the next day, she was back out.
ちゃんと脱出してる…w
She escaped properly... (lol)
スタッフの人が僕のこと知ってて
A staff member knew about me,
田中さんに預けようということで
and decided to entrust her to Tanaka-san...
持ってきてくれたんです
They brought her over to me.
で、バタバタしてたんでそのまま中身見ずに家に帰った
I was busy, so I brought her home without looking inside the bag.
家に帰ったら…
When I got home...
部屋の明かりが激しく明滅する
the lights in my room started flickering violently.
PC立ち上げてメールの返信しようと思っても
I turned on my PC to reply to emails,
音声認識ソフトが立ち上がって…他のアプリが開けない
speech recognition software started up and wouldn't let me open other apps.
で、なんか気になって袋を開けたら…この子が出てきた
Curious, I opened the bag, and this doll came out.
なるほど…その瞬間に現象が一気に止んだ
I see... At that exact moment, the phenomenon stopped instantly.
じゃあもう早く出してくれてっていうやつだったんですかね
So she was basically saying "get me out of here fast"?
メッセージをたぶん…
Maybe it was a message...
でもめっちゃ可愛い服まで着せて可愛がってますけど…
But she's dressed in cute clothes, looks like she's being loved...
生きてますね
She's living fine.
僕はこの場では仲良いフリしてますけど
I'm pretending to be friendly with her right now,
全然…可愛がってない？
Not loving her at all?
可愛がってないというか…敬ってます
Rather than affection... I show her respect.
そこから霊的な物とか魂みたいな物が宿るんじゃないかと思って
From there, I thought spiritual things or souls might inhabit objects.
現象が起きた時は怖くなかった？
Were you not scared when it happened?
いやめちゃくちゃ怖いです
No, I was extremely terrified.
ちゃんと怖かったんだ！
You were actually scared!
そういうの怖くないタイプなのかと思ってました
I thought you were the type who wouldn't be scared of such things.
めちゃくちゃ怖いです
I'm terrified.
次ちょっと…
Next, there's...
最近送られてきた
Something that was sent to me recently...
ものがあってそれ見てほしいんですけど
I have something I want to show you...
これなんですよ
This is it.
大量の…人形
A massive amount of... dolls.
すごいね…あの執着が
It's incredible... the fixation...
いやすごいなぁ…
Wow, that's intense...
「こんなにする？」ってくらいすごい遊び方してますね…
"To do this much?" It's such an intense way to play...
これ遊びじゃなくて…遊びじゃないんだ…
This wasn't playing... It wasn't playing...
姉妹の妹が姉を呪ってた
A younger sister was cursing her older sister.
えええええ〜…
Ehhhhh...
ず〜っと何年もお姉ちゃんの事を思って「◯ね◯ね◯ね」
For years, thinking about her sister, going "Die, die, die..."
そこまでする…！？
Going that far...!?
実際この姉妹がどうなったかと言うと
As for what actually happened to these sisters...
姉の方が精神病院に入院
The older sister was admitted to a psychiatric hospital.
妹も精神病院に入院 二人とも入院
Eventually, the younger sister was also admitted. Both ended up hospitalized.
あれとかないですか？はぁとさんは
Do you have anything like that, Haato-san?
呪いたい相手とか
Anyone you want to curse?
私が呪いたい相手…？いないですね 自分も呪った分だけの対価
Someone I want to curse...? No. If I curse someone, I have to pay the price for it...
払わなきゃいけないから そこまでしてやる必要はないかな…
So I don't think it's worth going that far...
“返ってくる”というのはありますね
There is the concept of it coming back to you.
返ってくるんだったらイヤです
If it comes back, then no thanks.
クイックに呪える
There is one that lets you cast a quick curse.
呪い教えてくれるんだw
You're teaching me curses? (lol)
呪ったりするんですか？
Do you curse people, Tanaka-san?
僕、呪ったりしますから
I do curse people.
誰呪うんですか？w
Who do you curse? (lol)
アンチをずっと呪ってます
I curse my anti-fans continuously.
これで一発 これは西アフリカの呪術師が作ってくれた
With this, one shot. A shaman in West Africa made this.
どういう効果があるかって言ったら
If you ask what kind of effect it has...
刺せるようになっている
It's designed to be pierced.
ここに呪いたい相手の名前を言う
You say the name of the person you want to curse here.
名前だけで良いんだ
Just the name is enough? Like a Death Note.
それでこう…刺すと…
Then when you stick it in like this...
そいつに不幸が訪れる
misfortune will fall upon them.
あの、ちなみに…この部屋の中で1番呪力が強い呪物ってあるんですか？
By the way... Is there a cursed object in this room with the strongest cursed power?
こんだけ集めてると なんか増えててもわからない場合がある
When you collect this many, sometimes you don't even notice if something new is added.
最近…これどこから責任もらった…？ 誰から誰からもらったのか
Recently... Where did I get this from...? Who gave it to me...
まったくわからへん 身に覚えがないぞっていう人形があるんですよ
I have no idea at all, I have no recollection of acquiring this doll.
え、見たいです ぜひお願いします
Eh, I want to see it! Please do.
すごい気持ち悪い人形なんですよ
It's a really creepy doll.
これなんですけどね
This is the one.
wwwww あれw あれ、タランちゃま…？w
(hahaha) Wait... Is that Taran-chama...? (lol)
どういう人が作ったんですかね…
I wonder what kind of person made this...
これ私のお姉ちゃんが作ったやつ…
My older sister made this...
はあとさんのお姉ちゃんが作ったんですか…？
Haato-san's older sister made it...?
私のお姉ちゃんが作った… クモのね…
My older sister made it... a spider, you see...
あ、これがね？
Ah, this is?
体もクモになってるんですよ。
Its body is also a spider.
けっこうセンスありますよね。
She actually has pretty good taste.
すごいですよね、これ。ぜひ置いておいてください。
Isn't it amazing? Please keep it here.
あっ、いいんですか？ じゃあ置いておこうかな…
Ah, is that okay? Then maybe I'll keep it...
呪いはない気もするけど…
I feel like there's no curse, but...
すごい馴染んでるｗ
It fits right in!
なんもない人形も こういう場所に置いておけば…
Even dolls with nothing about them, if placed in a spot like this...
え、大丈夫ですか？ 私のお姉ちゃんが作ったんですけど、お姉ちゃん呪われちゃったりとかしません？
Eh, is it okay? My older sister made it, but she won't get cursed or anything?
お姉ちゃん作ってるだけなんで…
Your sister was just making it, so...
あ、そっか。作ってただけか。わ、私…？
Ah, I see. She was just making it. Wh-What about me...?
でもね、これホンマに…ちょっと…嫌な事言いますけど…
But, you know, this is really... I'm going to say something a bit unpleasant...
えっ、なんですか？
Eh, what is it?
さっきから はあとさんの後ろに ずっと誰か居ますよね？
Ever since earlier, there's been someone behind you the whole time, right?
あんま言いたくなかったんですけど…
I didn't really want to say it, but...
ずっと誰かついてきてますよ
Someone's been following you this whole time.
え？
Huh?
待ったをかけた ちょっと考えた
Waited and waited, thought it over a bit
馬鹿な女 まんまとかかった
A foolish woman fell right into the trap
だからどうした？
So what?
自ら望んだと言ってんジャン
Didn't you say you wished for it yourself?
待ったをかけた ちょっと考えた
Waited and waited, thought it over a bit
少々ちょっと考えたから
Thought it over just a little bit
だからどうした？
So what?
お望み通りの末路です！
It's the exact end you wished for!
なんで なんで なんで なんで なんで
Why, why, why, why, why
なんでなの どういうつもり
Why is that? What do you mean?
なんで なんで なんで なんで なんで
Why, why, why, why, why
なぁんだ そんなもんか
What is it, is that all there is?
ド屑
[Title: Total Scum]
まぁそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いナイ
Well, that's just how it is, that's how things are / I'm sure of it, there's no doubt
まぁそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 絶対に
Well, that's just how it is, that's how things are / I'm sure of it, absolutely
まぁそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いナイ
Well, that's just how it is, that's how things are / I'm sure of it, there's no doubt
まぁそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いナイの
Well, that's just how it is, that's how things are / I'm sure of it, without a doubt
違いナイよ 絶対
Without a doubt, absolutely
待ったをかけた ちょっとためらった
Waited and waited, hesitated a bit
確かにためらった
I definitely hesitated
なんだかなぁ なんだかなぁ
How odd, how strange
こういうことではない
This isn't how it's supposed to be
待ったをかけた ちょっとためらった
Waited and waited, hesitated a bit
なんだ なんだ なんなんだ あなた
What, what, what on earth are you?
だから だから
Therefore, therefore
こんなことは望んでないから
Because I never wished for anything like this
なんで なんで なんで なんで なんで
Why, why, why, why, why
なんでなの どういうつもり
Why is that? What do you mean?
なんで なんで なんで なんで
Why, why, why, why
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me
従え 従え 従え
Obey, obey, obey
君に一切の拒否権ないよ
You have no right to refuse at all
黙って従え
Shut up and obey
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me
従え 従え 従え
Obey, obey, obey
お願い お願い お願い お願い
Please, please, please, please
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me
従え 従え 従え
Obey, obey, obey
従え 従えって言ってんの
Obey, I said obey
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me
従え 従え 従え
Obey, obey, obey
お願い お願い お願い お願い お願い
Please, please, please, please, please
ということで サロメちゃんに来てもらったよ〜！
And with that, Salome-chan is here with us~!
壱、十、百、千、満点サロメ！ 皆様方を100満点の笑顔にさせますわ！
One, ten, hundred, thousand, Perfect Score Salome! I will make everyone smile with a 100-point smile!
今はまだ一般人、いつかお嬢様になりたい！ そして今日ははあと様をお祝いに来ました！
Currently just a commoner, wanting to become a refined lady someday! And today, I came to celebrate Haato-sama!
100満点原サロメでございますわ〜！ / サロメちゃん！
I am Hyakumantenbara Salome~! / Salome-chan!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
「ド屑」一緒に歌えてすごく嬉しい！ 歌ってみたも本当に最高でした！
I'm so happy we got to sing "Dokuzu" together! The cover video was truly amazing too!
普段お上品なサロメちゃんのヤンデレ感がたまりませんでした！
The yandere vibe from the usually refined Salome-chan was irresistible!
歌声も喋り方も性格も 好きです！
Your singing voice, speech, and personality—I love them all!
はあと様 本当にありがとうございますわ〜！ / こちらこそ〜！
Haato-sama, thank you so very much~! / Likewise~!
なんかこうやってご縁が繋がって、こうやって今一緒に歌えたのがすごく嬉しいですわ〜！
I'm so happy that our connection brought us together to sing like this now~!
私にもはあと様のこともぜんぶ可愛いと思ってるですし、ほんとに…可愛い！
I also think everything about Haato-sama is so cute, truly... so cute!
おめでとう！ / 今日は本当にありがとうございました、はあと様！
Congratulations! / Thank you so much for today, Haato-sama!
こちらこそありがとう！
Thank you as well!
さようなら、またね〜！ / またね〜！
Goodbye, see you later~! / See you~!
モエチャッカファイア
[Title: Moechakka Fire]
ようこそお越しなさったご主人様
Welcome, master
隣に座って せーの 萌え 萌え 萌え 萌え
Sit next to me, ready, go: Moe, moe, moe, moe
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ ねぇ教えて
Who would be happy with this? Hey, tell me
Loud, turn it up, Up-Up
愛想忘れてご苦労様
Thanks for your hard work without even a smile.
渡したあなたでせーの Ruff Ruff Ruff Ruff
From me to you, ready, set: Ruff Ruff Ruff Ruff!
こんなので誰かが喜ぶの？ Say! 理由教えて 笑顔で Up-Up
Does someone actually like this? Say! Tell me why, with a smile, Up-Up!
ひらりひらり 女の子
Lightly, delicately, a girl fluttering...
ふわりふわり 言葉の層
Softly, gently, layers of words...
それでつまり 治めなくちゃ
So in short, I've got to keep control...
感情的リアル 笑顔で Up-Up
An emotional reality, with a smile, Up-Up!
人は見かけによらぬもの
You can't judge a person by their cover.
噂じゃ見抜けまい
You can't see through them just from rumors.
舌足らずの袖獅子の皮
Lisping tongues, hiding in a lion's skin...
鳥肌 サメ肌 アンダー
Goosebumps, sharkskin, down below...
間違ったご指名を頂きます
Thank you for your mistaken designation!
渡したあなたでせーの Ruff Ruff Ruff Ruff
From me to you, ready, set: Ruff Ruff Ruff Ruff!
これはド派手にご苦労様
What a showy standard of hard work!
遊びましょう 笑顔で Up-Up
Let us play, with a smile, Up-Up!
ひらりひらり ここわの層
Lightly, delicately, layers of words...
ふわりふわり そこ連勝
Softly, gently, a winning streak right there...
それでつまり 治めなくちゃ
So in short, I've got to keep control...
衝動的リアル 笑顔で Up-Up
Impulsive reality, with a smile, Up-Up!
歌い出す 秘密の彼
Sing out, the secret lover...
終わることのない この世界
This world that never ends...
悲しい子供は 虚しい子供は
Sad children, empty children...
眠らせて
Put them to sleep...
おままごと 遊びましょう 笑顔で Up-Up
Playing house, let us play, with a smile, Up-Up!
ひらりひらり 女の子
Lightly, delicately, a girl fluttering...
ふわりふわり 言葉の層
Softly, gently, layers of words...
それでつまり 治めなくちゃ
So in short, I've got to keep control...
感情的リアル 笑顔で Up-Up
Emotional reality, with a smile, Up-Up!
遊びましょう 笑顔で Up-Up
Let us play, with a smile, Up-Up!
Up-Up
星川～！
Hoshikawa~!
誕生祭おめでとう！ありがとう来てくれて！
Happy Birthday Festival! Thank you for coming!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
なんとね、2021年の、4年ぶりに…
Can you believe it, for the first time in 4 years since 2021...
出てくれました！
...she appeared here with me!
「チューリングラブ」だったの覚えてる？
Do you remember it was "Turing Love"?
覚えてるよ！4年前に！
I remember! Four years ago!
そう！あん時はね、若かった…
Yeah! Back then, we were so young...
え、今はなんか違う？
Eh, is it different now?
いや、でもクールになったんだよね！
No, but we've gotten cooler!
我々今日、ね、クール可愛かったもんね！
Today we were cool and cute, right?
確かにね、いつもの「チューリングラブ」こんなことしてたよね？
True! For "Turing Love", we did something like this, right?
なんか、オタ芸とかしてたからね！
Yeah, we were doing wota-gei and stuff!
こんなことしてたのに、だいぶクールになりました。
Even though we did that back then, we've become quite cool.
どうしたの？
What happened?
ちょっと…
A bit...
リアルすぎるだろ！
That's way too realistic!
どういうこと？
What's that supposed to mean?
わかんないよ！写真とか…あ、そうね！
I don't know! Like taking photos... Oh right!
今日ね、歌った「モエチャッカファイア」ね、歌ってみた動画も出してるので、ぜひ見てください！
Today we sang "Moe Chakka Fire", and we also released a cover video of it, so please check it out!
え、なんでこの曲にしてくれたんですか？
Eh, why did you choose this song?
えー、これ歌いたかった！
Ah, because I really wanted to sing it!
やっぱね、歌ってみたも出したし、誕生祭でもね、一緒に歌いたいなと思って選びました！
Well, since we released a cover of it, I wanted to sing it together in my birthday stream too, so I picked it!
おー！なんか意外な選曲だった、個人的には。
Oooh! Personally, I felt it was a surprisingly unexpected song choice.
え、本当？なんか今回ホラーライブがテーマなんだけど、
Really? Well, this time the theme is "Horror Live",
どんなコンセプトのライブ？！見たことない！
What kind of concept live is that?! I've never seen that before!
ちょっと合うかなと思って。
I thought it would fit well.
ああ、なるほどね！ちょっと落ち着いててね。
Ah, I see! Being a bit calm and subdued.
なんか、一緒に写真とか撮る？
Should we take some photos together?
撮る！撮る！ってかすごいマジでライブステージ！
Let's do it! Let me tell you, this live stage is seriously amazing!
ねー！めちゃかわいい！
Right?! It's super cute!
え、なんかいいポーズ…やりたいポーズある？まずは普通な？
Eh, any good poses... Any pose you want to do? First a normal one?
まずね！イエーイ！
First, yeah! Yay!
パシャ！え、かわいい！パシャパシャ！
*Snap!* Eh, cute! *Snap snap!*
きっと撮ってくれてるでしょう！
I'm sure everyone is taking screenshots!
あとは？ハート？
What else? A heart?
ハート？ハート作っとく？
A heart? Should we make a heart?
出来てる？
Are we doing it right?
いい感じー！いい感じー！
Looks good~! Looks good~!
にょき！
Nyoki!
にょきにょき！
Nyoki nyoki!
あとは？
What else?
えーあと何だろう？なんかでかくね…あ、これこれこれ！
Hmm, what else? Something big... Oh, this one, this one!
やだー！
No way!
うわー！
Woah!
って感じでね！
Something like that!
あれは？4年前にもさ、撮ったさ、ちょっと座ってエモめな…
What about that? The one we took 4 years ago, sitting down to look emotional...
こっちじゃない！みんなの方向いてね！
Not this way! Facing everyone!
あ、いい！いいじゃん！
Ah, good! That's nice!
4年前もこれで撮ったんだよ！
We took a picture like this four years ago, too!
イエーイ！みんな見てる～？
Yay! Is everyone watching~?
久しぶりの星ちゃまー！
Hoshi-chama after so long~!
衣装も変わってね！
Our outfits changed, too!
本当だね、2人とも衣装変わった！
That's true, both of our outfits changed!
ねぇ、めちゃ可愛いその衣装！しかもめちゃ脚…
Hey, that outfit is super cute! Plus, your legs...
これはでも間違え…脚フェチに向けた衣装だから！いや、そっちじゃない！
Well, this outfit was made for leg fetishists after all! No, not that!
結構隠してるけど...
It's mostly covered up, but...
いやいや、この脚よ！
No, no, look at these legs!
違う、隠してるのが逆にいいんだって！
No, being covered up makes it even better!
あ、そういうこと？チラ見えのね。
Ah, is that it? The sneaky peek-a-boo look.
わかってないなー。
You really don't get it.
やばい、画角やばい！
Oh no, this camera angle is crazy!
だいぶな画角じゃなかったよ。
That was quite an extreme camera angle.
絶対領域がね...
That absolute territory, right...
どう？なんかセクシーポーズとかしなくて大丈夫？
Are you sure you don't need to do a sexy pose?
セクシーポーズ？
A sexy pose?
したいの？
Do you want to?
大丈夫かな？いや、大丈夫です！
Is it okay? No, I'm good!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
あ、ありがとう！
Ah, thank you!
またね、なんか一緒に歌って踊りたい！
I'd love to sing and dance with you again!
うん！踊ろう、是非！
Yeah! Let me dance with you!
是非ともまた次も踊りましょう！
Let's definitely dance together next time too!
踊りましょう！
Let me dance with you!
じゃあ、バイバーイ！
Well then, bye-bye!
バイバイ！頑張ってね！
Bye-bye! Good luck!
ありがとう！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
正しくなれない切りがどこをみても
Can't be right, no matter where I look in this fog,
片っ端から確かめたくて
I want to make sure of everything, one by one.
考え続けたい 偽りで出会えた
I want to keep thinking, meeting through fake pretenses,
僕らは何ひとつも 奪われてないから
None of us has had a single thing taken away.
僕ら育っていくみたい
It feels like we are growing up,
愛されるみたい 暖かな波を詠む
as if being loved, reciting the warm waves.
過去か今を選ぶ
Choosing between the past or the present,
澄んだ浅黄色 尋ねる声で何度でも
in a clear light blue voice asking again and again.
僕ら 嘘つきだね
We are liars, aren't we?
両思いだね
Our feelings are mutual, aren't they?
枯れ果てるまで 泣き笑い今日を受け入れてく
Until we wither, we accept today with tears and laughter.
喜び合った日々を 忘れ出しそうだけど
We seem on the verge of forgetting the happy days, but...
知らない方が幸せだって
They say ignorance is bliss,
知れば知れるほど...
but the more I learn, the more...
正しくなれない切りがどこをみても
Can't be right, no matter where I look in this fog,
片っ端から確かめたくて
I want to make sure of everything, one by one.
考え続けたい 偽りで出会えた
I want to keep thinking, meeting through fake pretenses,
僕らは何ひとつも 奪われてないから
None of us has had a single thing taken away.
今心を閉ざすように
As if closing our hearts right now,
粛々と遅れを続けよう 枯れ木に笑顔だけ
let's quietly keep running behind, with only smiles on withered trees.
君の肉体欲しい すべて
I want your physical form, all of it,
無駄になんかさせないよ
I won't let any of it go to waste.
ねぇ 知り得る限り幸せだって
Hey, as far as I can know, even if it's happiness,
たどり着いてもいい...
it's fine even if we reach it...
君だけがみる夕焼け 影かがみ
The sunset only you see, reflected shadow,
僕でもいつかわかる日まで
until the day comes when even I can understand it.
考え続けたい 偽りで会えた
I want to keep thinking, meeting through fake pretenses,
確かになる枝分かれよ 導かれ
dividing branches that become certainty, being guided.
大したもんじゃない 無駄なもんじゃない
It's nothing grand, it's not useless,
潮のりを歓待にしてくように
as if welcoming the salty tide.
ずっと もうずっと 茶化されようが
Forever, forever, even if we are made fun of,
折れない強さは
an unyielding strength...
可能性が
The possibilities...
広げるならば
If they expand...
可能性を 諦められないから
Because I can't give up on the possibilities,
まだ...
Not yet...
正しくなれない切りがどこをみても
Can't be right, no matter where I look in this fog,
片っ端から確かめたくて
I want to make sure of everything, one by one.
考え続けたい 偽りで出会えた
I want to keep thinking, meeting through fake pretenses,
僕らは何ひとつも
None of us has...
すべて嫌われても 奪われてないから
Even if hated by everything, had a single thing taken away.
はあちゃま！
Haachama!
大好きだよ！
I love you so much!
はあちゃま...
Haachama...
はあちゃま、私も大好き！
Haachama, I love you too!
今まで...
Until now...
ごめん！
I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい！
I'm so sorry!
いなくなって...
Leaving you behind...
寂しかったよ...
I was so lonely...
いつも側にいるって言ったじゃん！
You told me you'd always be by my side!
ずっと待ってたよ...
I was waiting for you the whole time...
あ、ちゃま？
Oh, Chama?
あ、ちゃまちゃま！ちゃまだよ〜！
Ah, Chama-chama! It's Chama~!
こうやって対話するの、初めてだよね！
It's our first time talking like this, isn't it!
さっき歌ってた感触、最高だったよー！
Singing together earlier felt amazing!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
なんか大人っぽくなったね！
You've gotten somewhat mature!
実は最近、旅をすることが増えまして…
Actually, I've been traveling more lately...
そこで新しい自分を見つけて、ちょっぴり大人っぽい曲にチャレンジしてみました！
I found a new side of myself there, so I tried challenging a slightly more mature song!
特に好きな歌詞とかはある？
Are there any lyrics you particularly like?
はい。「もう一度もう一度と思いが何度あったでしょう」という歌詞がありまして…
Yes. There's a line that goes, "How many times did I think, 'Just once more, once more'?"...
出会った景色や人の温もりを思いながら、すごく感情移入しました！
While thinking of the sights and human warmth I encountered, I really resonated with it!
そうなんだ！今日リリース予定なので、みんなもたくさん聴いてね！
I see! It's scheduled for release today, so everyone, please listen to it a lot!
そしてぜひぜひ、デュエットで『正しくなれない』歌ったよー！
And we also sang "Can't Be Right" as a duet!
どうだった？
How was it?
今までの記憶とか葛藤を振り返りながらでね、すごく心に沁みましたね。
Looking back on our memories and struggles so far, it really touched my heart.
本当だよー！はぁちゃんはさ、ずっと塞ぎ込んで、全然はあちゃまのこと見向きもしないんだもん！
Really! Ha-chan was moping around for so long, not even looking at Haachama at all!
そんなことないけど…ごめんね。でもお互い知り合って理解し合えたから、良かったなって思うよ。
That's not true, but... I'm sorry. But since we got to know and understand each other, I'm glad.
あ〜、ならいっか！
Ah, guess it's fine then!
そんな2人の家族写真も、今回は撮ってもらいました！
We also had a family photo of the two of us taken this time!
イェーイ！2人の仲良しの証！
Yay! Proof of how close we are!
はい！B2タペストリーになっておりますー！
Yes! It's available as a B2 tapestry!
おしゃれー！
So stylish!
はあちゃま、行くよ！せーの！
Haachama, here we go! Ready, set!
みんな、ゲットしてくださいー！
Everyone, please get one~!
お人形
[Song: Doll]
ねぇ見て お気に入りの
Look, my favorite...
世界に一つの お人形さん
one-and-only doll in the world.
顔も性格も 違ったけど
Our faces and personalities were different,
ずっとみんな なかよし
but we were always good friends.
「苦しい」を教わったとき
When I was taught what "painful" meant,
私にもできた 恩返し
I was able to give back too.
大事な人 好きな人
Someone precious, someone I love,
いつもそばにいてほしい よね
I want you to always stay by my side, you know.
上手に縫ってね
Sew me up nicely,
私にしてくれたように
just like you did for me.
少しほつれたとことか
Places that are a little frayed,
めちゃ可愛いね
are super cute, aren't they?
身体もたくさん
All those body parts,
好きに繋ぎあわせて
stitch them together as you like.
少し歪だけどね
They're a bit distorted, though.
大切な家族たちなの
They are my precious family.
ねぇみて お気に入りの
Look, my favorite...
せかいにひとつの おにんぎょうさん
one-and-only doll in the world.
かおもせいかくも ちがったけど
Our faces and personalities were different,
ずっとみんな なかよし
but we were always good friends.
なかよし なかよし なかよし なかよし なかよし
Good friends, good friends, good friends, good friends, good friends...
やさしい うれしい
Kind, happy,
たのしい いとしい
fun, beloved.
ほめて なでて
Praise me, pat me.
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
上手に縫ってね
Sew me up nicely,
私にしてくれたように
just like you did for me.
少し解れたとことか
Places that are a little unraveled,
めちゃ可愛いね
are super cute, aren't they?
身体もたくさん
All those body parts,
好きに繋ぎあわせて
stitch them together as you like.
少し歪だけどね
They're a bit distorted, though.
大切な 大切な
My precious, my precious...
たいせつな だいせつな だいせつな かぞくたちなの
precious, precious, precious family.
たいせつな かぞくたちなの
They are my precious family.
生誕ライブ限定！グッズ販売のお知らせ！
Birthday Live Limited! Merch Sale Announcement!
家族写真B2タペストリー！
Family Photo B2 Tapestry!
ゴージャスな額縁風デザインと
With a gorgeous frame-style design,
肖像画のような二人がとってもキュート！
the two looking like a portrait are so cute!
お部屋の壁に、今日の思い出を飾って
Decorate your room's wall with today's memories,
彩り豊かな推し活ができちゃいます！
and you can enjoy a colorful fan life!
おでかけちゃまぬいぐるみ！
Outing-Chama Plushie!
ボタン風の目がとっても可愛いぬいぐるみ！
A plushie with super cute button-style eyes!
丁寧にひとつひとつ再現されたドレス衣装のちゃまと
With Chama meticulously detailed in a dress outfit,
一緒におでかけして旅に出られちゃいます！
you can go out on trips together!
鞄に付けられるハートチャーム付き！
Includes a heart charm that can be attached to your bag!
タランちゃまぬいぐるみポーチ！
Taran-Chama Plushie Pouch!
あのタランちゃまがポーチに？！
That Taran-Chama... is a pouch?!
背中のファスナーが開いて収納できる便利アイテム！
A convenient item with a zipper on the back for storage!
ゴスロリ衣装のタランちゃまが可愛すぎる！
Goth-Loli Taran-Chama is way too cute!
チェーンがついてるから安心して、お外にお散歩させられるよ！
It comes with a chain, so you can safely take it for a walk outside!
タランちゃますまほリング！
Taran-Chama Smartphone Ring!
スマホの落下はタランちゃまにお任せ！
Leave preventing your phone from dropping to Taran-Chama!
しっかり張り付いて守ってくれます！
It sticks firmly and protects your phone!
愛くるしいお目目と、つい目が合っちゃう瞬間も
With adorable eyes, even the moments your eyes accidentally meet...
癒されてたまりません！
...are irresistibly soothing!
フルセットは数量限定もあります！
The full set is also available in limited quantities!
フルセット購入特典の数量限定バージョンは、箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと、赤井はあと直筆サイン！
The limited quantity version of the full set bonus comes with a foil-stamped message postcard and Haato Akai's handwritten autograph!
特典ボイス「ひみつのはなし」もあるよ！プロモカードもあるよ！
Includes a bonus voice track "Secret Story", and a promo card too!
ホロライブ公式ECサイトで販売中！
On sale now at the Hololive Official EC Site!